GALANG (Glen)

PHAM

"I am passionate and prideful about my work no matter the job or task and believe expectations are meant to be exceeded."

SUMMARY

Driven professional with broad technical and soft skill sets who thrives in fast paced environments. 8 years of military experience has instilled leadership, c communication, teamwork, and tenacity. Known for ability to meet deadlines and translate ideas into testable, maintainable, readable and reliable code.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Trance Trader Full Stack Application github.com/glenrage/trance-trader

Full Stack Stock Market Portfolio application. Users can manage their own stock portfolio and simulate stock trades with updated portfolio data. Built with React, Node, Express, and MongoDb.

Equi-Gallery-VR Full Stack Application

github.com/glenrage/Equi-Gallery-VR

Lead developer in creating full stack application with Mongo, Node, Express, Angular. It allows photographers to create a personalized gallery to upload 360* photos and view them in virtual reality with VR supported devices.

Effort Manager Back End Server Application

github.com/CF-8-week-challenge/effort-manager

Lead developer in creating back end server for an iOS development team for a fitness app that tracks daily challenges with members organized in groups. RESTful API built with Mongo, Node, Express.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Oct 2016 - Present Full Stack Web Developer

Self Taught / Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

Learned Advanced Software Development in JavaScript. Implemented industry's best practices in writing quality, maintainable code and development processes. Integrated data through back end services and frameworks.

2006 - 2014 U.S Air Force (Supervisor, MX Data Analyst)

McChord AFB, WA, Worldwide multiple

Led and supervised aircraft maintenance teams on multiple deployments to hazardous combat zones. Managed planning and development of maintenance metrics reports. Performed maintenance data analysis in GO-81 to efficiently reduce unnecessary maintenance tasks by 20%.

EDUCATION

Feb - June 2017 Full Stack Web Development Intensive

Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

2009 - 2013 Bachelor of Science in Technical Management

Embry - Riddle Aeronautical University - Daytona Beach, FL

11018 27th AVE NE (916) 280-3229 Seattle, WA, 98125

phamgalang@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.glenrage.com/glenrage

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript/jQuery HTML5/CSS/SASS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core

Object Oriented/Functional Programming
MVC
RESTful API
Continuous Integration

Test/Behavior Driven Development

Debugging Documenta-

Framework/Database

Angular

React/React Native

Express

Node

Passport

BootStrap

Redux

MongoDB

PostgresSQL

Testing Frameworks

Mocha/Chai Jasmine/Karma

Systems/Tools

Microsoft Windows Mac OSX Git version control AWS Webpack

SPOKEN LAN-GUAGES

English (Fluent)
Vietnamese (Fluent)